Register of the Lyn Nofziger Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Lyn Nofziger Papers
1919-2004
2010C32
Hoover Institution Archives
20 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 videotape, 1 motion picture reel (8 linear feet)
The papers primarily consist of Nofziger's writings as reporter, political consultant, writer and satirical poet; collected materials relating to political conditions in California and the United States, and documents generated from work with Republican candidates including Richard M. Nixon and Ronald Reagan. Also included are materials regarding United States vs. Nofziger pertaining to his alleged violation of the Ethics in Government Act.
Nofziger, Lyn
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2010.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Citizens for Reagan Records, Hoover Institution Archives
Allen Drury papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Bonner Frank Fellers papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Robert C. Hill papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Hoover Institution and the Gorbachev Foundation (Moscow) collection, Hoover Institution Archives
John D. Lodge papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
1924 June 8 Born, Bakersfield, CA
1947 September 12 Married Bonnie Jean Foster
1950 BA, San Jose State College
1950-1966 Copley Newspapers and News Service, reporter, editor, and Washington correspondent
1966 Press secretary, Ronald Reagan's California gubernatorial campaign
1967-1968 Director of communications for California Governor Ronald Reagan
1968-1969 Political consultant
1969-1971 Deputy assistant for Congressional Relations for President Richard Nixon
1971-1972 Deputy chair of communications, Republican National Committee
1972 Executive director, California Committee to Re-elect President Nixon
1973-1975, 1979-1980 Political consultant
1975 July-1976 August Press secretary, California campaign director, convention director, Ronald Reagan's presidential primary campaign
1976 September-November Special projects, Gerald Ford's presidential campaign
1977-1979 Executive vice chair, Citizens for the Republic Political Action Committee
1979 March-August Deputy chair of finance, Ronald Reagan presidential campaign
1979-1980 Political consultant
1980-1981 Press secretary, Ronald Reagan presidential campaign
1981 January-1982 January Assistant to the President for political affairs for President Ronald Reagan
1982-1987 Nofziger & Bragg Communications, political and government consulting
1984 Senior adviser, Reagan presidential re-election campaign
1986 Indicted for violation of the Ethics in Government Act
1988 January-April United States v. Nofziger trial
1988-2006 Political and government consultant, Nofziger Communications
1988 November 22-1989 June 27 Appeal argued, United States v. Nofziger
1990 January 10 Original indictment dismissed, United States v. Nofziger
1992 Author, Nofziger (memoir), published by Regnery Gateway
2000 April 10 Author, Unbridled Joy: The Verse of Joy Skilmer, published by MND Books
2004 May Author, The Tacketts published by Jameson Books
2006 March 27 Died, Falls Church, Virginia
Source: Contemporary Authors Online, Gale, 2010. Reproduced in Biography Resource Center. Farmington Hills, Mich.: Gale, 2010. http://galenet.galegroup.com/servlet/BioRC
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers primarily consist of Nofziger's writings as reporter, political consultant, writer and satirical poet; collected materials relating to political conditions in California and the United States; and documents generated from work with Republican candidates including Richard M. Nixon and Ronald Reagan. Also included are materials regarding United States v. Nofziger pertaining to his alleged violation of the Ethics in Government Act.
One of the most significant aspects of Nofziger's career was his work as a political consultant for candidates at federal and state levels. While he worked for several Republican candidates, two of the most prominent were Richard Nixon and Ronald Reagan. In the Richard Nixon administration records are correspondence and associated documents involving Nixon and key members of his staff such as H. R. Haldeman and Charles Colson, as well as the California Committee for the Re-election of the President, which played a significant role in Nixon's re-election campaign in 1972.
Nofziger shared a strong affiliation with Ronald Reagan. The Ronald Reagan related materials reflect that affiliation through letters, memoranda and collected printed items. The bulk of the materials are Reagan's speeches and writings, Nofziger's writings specifically related to Ronald Reagan, writings by others regarding Reagan and newspaper clippings and other print media from Reagan's gubernatorial and presidential terms. Photographs also include a collection of autographed images presented to Nofziger by high ranking officials in the first Reagan presidential administration.
Nofziger was also a political consultant for candidates such as Ed Reinecke, Bob Dole, and Pat Buchanan. The Political consulting records documents this work. Campaign paraphernalia from candidates Nofziger supported is present in Memorabilia.
Speeches and writings offer an insight into the evolution of thought and philosophy for the American conservative movement and the Republican Party from Nofziger's candid and uncensored point of view. The writings consist of newspaper articles, speeches, personal reflections, and commentaries in drafts and printed copies.
Nofziger was prosecuted on charges of violating the Ethics in Government Act for illegally lobbying for the Wedtech Corporation for federal defense contracts shortly after resigning from Reagan's first presidential administration. Many of the documents relevant to the indictment, trial, appeal, and subsequent dismissal of the charges are included in the Legal proceedings and related documents.
Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Reagan, Ronald.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); California--Politics and government--1951-; Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Presidents--United States--Election--1980.; Sound recordings.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989.
- Personal File, 1919, 1972-1983, undated (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes biographies, personal correspondence, family records, and hand-drawn sketches of Nofziger. Arranged by document type.
  - Biographies, 1968, 1970 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Family background information, 1919 March 19 (Folder 1: 2)
    Includes a family tree and other documents regarding Nofziger's family since 1919
  - Integrated Communications Systems contract with the State of California, 1978 November 30 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Letters and postcards from family, undated (Folder 1: 4)
  - Letters and postcards from friends, circa 1982, undated (Folder 1: 5)
  - Nofziger, Rosalind, records, 1972, 1975-1976 (Folder 1: 6)
    Copy of a letter and legal document regarding Rosalind Nofziger (Lyn Nofziger's mother)
  - Quotes collected by Nofziger, undated (Folder 1: 7)
  - Sketches of Nofziger, undated (Folder 1: 8)
    Includes a sketch by Mike Peters
  - Miscellany, undated (Folder 1: 9)
- Speeches and Writings, 1963-2004, undated (Box 1-5)
  Consists of drafts and printed transcripts of speeches, broadcasts, interviews and panels; drafts and printed copies of articles, and personal writings. Press releases, reviews and correspondence about his printed works, primarily focusing on his autobiography, Nofziger, are also present. Arranged in three groups: speeches, writings, and interview transcripts.
  - Speeches, 1973-2000s (Folder 1-2)
    - 1973-1975 (Folder 1: 10)
    - circa 1970 (Folder 1: 11)
    - circa 1980-1988 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1981-1982 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 1982 (Folder 1: 14)
    - circa 1982-1983 (Folder 1: 15)
    - 1983 (Folder 1: 16)
    - 1984 (Folder 1: 17)
    - 1986, circa 1980s (Folder 2: 1)
    - 1988 March 11 (Folder 2: 2)
      Speech at the Manufacturer's Executive Conference
    - circa 1980s (Folder 2: 3-4)
    - circa 1980s-2000s (Folder 2: 5)
    - 1995 (Folder 2: 6)
    - circa 1995 (Folder 2: 7)
    - 1990s (Folder 2: 8)
  - Writings, circa 1980s-1996 (Folder 2-4)
    - "The Cultural Issue,", circa 1996 (Folder 2: 9)
    - "Media in the War of Ideas: Spectator and Participant,", circa 1980s (Folder 2: 10)
    - "A Reaganite's Lament,", circa 1991 (Folder 2: 11)
      Includes related correspondence regarding this article
    - "Reagan as Political Leader,", circa 1980s (Folder 2: 12)
      Includes related documents, 1990
    - Book reviews written by Nofziger, circa 1990s (Folder 2: 13)
    - Copley Newspaper records, 1963, 1966 (Folder 2: 14)
    - Letters to the press, 1978, 1988, 1990 (Folder 2: 15)
    - Clippings, 1953-1999 (Folder 2-4)
      - circa 1953-1963. Copley News Service, "Capital Corpone" articles (Folder 2: 16)
      - 1964 (Folder 2: 17)
      - circa 1965 (Folder 2: 18)
      - 1960s. Articles regarding the Panama Canal (Folder 3: 1)
      - 1960s (Folder 3: 2-5)
      - 1980s (Folder 4: 1)
      - circa 1992-1993. Includes drafts of columns (Folder 4: 2)
      - 1999 (Folder 4: 3)
      - 1990s (Folder 4: 4)
    - Nofziger, circa 1991-1992 (Folder 4: 5-6)
      Includes correspondence between Nofziger and Regnery Gateway Incorporated, the publishers for his autobiography and related documents and related documents
    - "Joy Skilmer" verse and publications, 1990s-2004 (Folder 4)
      - "Joy Skilmer" verse, 1990s-2000s (Folder 4: 7)
        Includes index of first lines of the verse present
      - O Joy! Occasional Verse from Joy Skilmer, circa 2000 (Folder 4: 8)
      - Miscellaneous verse, 1990s-2000s (Folder 4: 9-10)
      - "Titles all,", 2004 (Folder 4: 11)
      - Unbridled Joy: the Verse of Joy Skilmer, 2000 (Folder 4: 12)
        Includes printed copy and typed draft
    - Book reviews, circa 1992, undated (Folder 4: 13)
      Includes drafts and clippings for various book reviews and commentaries
  - Interview transcripts, 1966, 1982-2003, undated (Folder 5)
    - Interview by Sarah Sharp while Nofziger served as Reagan's press secretary, 1986 (Folder 5: 1)
    - Interview with David Brinkley, 1982, as part of a panel alongside Alan Greenspan and John D. Lofton Jr. (Folder 5: 2)
    - Ripon forum interview, 1984 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Darman questionnaire, 1986 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Interview with David Brinkley, 1988, as part of a panel alongside Senator Carl H. Levin, Representative Barney Frank, Representative Lynn Martin, and Lloyd Cutler. (Folder 5: 3)
    - Interview with Larry King, 1999, as part of a panel alongside Michael Deaver, Ken Duberstein, Ed Rollins, David Gergen, and Anne Compton. Undated interview (Folder 5: 3)
    - Interview, Miller Center of Public Affairs, 2003 September 30 (Folder 5: 4)
      Interview done as part of President Ronald Reagan Oral History Project
- Correspondence, Bulk, 1981-1985; 1962-1992, bulk 1981-1985 (Box 5-6)
  Contains correspondence with various associates and colleagues as well as correspondence in which Nofziger was copied. The majority of the correspondence is from groups and individuals with last name going from A to C. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. See also the Richard Nixon administrative records and the Ronald Reagan materials.
  - Abrams, Elliott, 1983-1984 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Alexander, Herbert E., 1982 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Alexander, Holmes, 1983-1984 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Allen, Richard, 1981, 1984 (Folder 5: 8-9)
  - Allison, Ed, 1983 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Ames, Al, 1983 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Anderson, William F., 1984 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Andrews, John K., 1984 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Annunzio, Frank, 1983 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Antonovich, Michael D., 1985 (Folder 5: 15)
  - Applebaum, Irwin, 1984 (Folder 5: 16)
  - Armendaris, Alex, 1983 (Folder 5: 17)
  - Arnett, G. Ray, 1983-1984 (Folder 5: 18)
  - Aronoff, Stanley J., 1984 (Folder 5: 19)
  - Ashton-Taylor, Ruth, 1985 (Folder 5: 20)
  - Atwater, Lee, 1983 (Folder 5: 21)
    Includes correspondence from Wayne LaPierre, director of the National Rifle Association
  - Auerbach, Ed, 1983, 1985 (Folder 5: 22)
  - Beckman, Peter, 1985 (Folder 5: 23)
  - Bell, Susan, 1985 (Folder 5: 24)
  - Blackwell, Morton, 1983 (Folder 5: 25)
  - Brock, Bill, 1972 November-December (Folder 5: 26)
  - Buchanan, Bay, 1970 (Folder 5: 27)
  - Cafferio, Anthony J., 1980-1984 (Folder 5: 28)
  - California Political Week, 1985 (Folder 5: 29)
  - Callahan, Gene, 1983, 1985 (Folder 5: 30)
  - Campbell, Don, 1983 (Folder 5: 31)
  - Campbell, Truman, 1983-1985, 1987 (Folder 5: 32)
  - Cannon, Lou, 1982 (Folder 5: 33)
  - Capen, Richard, 1984 (Folder 5: 34)
  - Cardenas, Mike, 1981 (Folder 5: 35)
  - Carey, Norval, 1983 (Folder 5: 36)
  - Carl, Hazel M., 1984 (Folder 5: 37)
  - Carleson, Robert, 1983 (Folder 5: 38)
  - Carlin, Paul N., 1985 (Folder 5: 39)
  - Carmen, Gerald, 1983 (Folder 5: 40)
  - Carpenito, James R., 1983 (Folder 5: 41)
  - Carroll, John S., 1984-1985 (Folder 5: 42)
  - Carter, Harlon B., 1983 (Folder 5: 43)
  - Cashell, Robert A., 1983 (Folder 5: 44)
  - Castille, Ronald, 1985 (Folder 5: 45)
  - Caulfield, Jack, 1983 (Folder 5: 46)
  - Cavaney, Red, 1983 (Folder 5: 47)
  - Cervantes, Rudy, 1985 (Folder 5: 48)
  - Chagall, David, 1983 (Folder 5: 49)
  - Chapman, Bruce, 1985 (Folder 5: 50)
  - Chien, Frederick F., 1985 (Folder 5: 51)
  - Cherry, Linda, 1985 (Folder 5: 52)
  - Christina, Vernon, 1983 (Folder 5: 53)
  - Clark, William P., 1981, 1983 (Folder 5: 54)
  - Climaco, John, 1981-1982 (Folder 5: 55)
  - Coffman, M. R., 1983 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1985 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Coleman-Miller, Beverly, 1984 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Collins, Arnold, 1984 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Collins, B. T., undated (Folder 6: 5)
  - Connor, Hal, 1983 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Cooper, Joe, 1983 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Coors, Joe, 1981 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Courtemancher, Jack L., 1984, 1991 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Coyne, Marshall, 1984 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Cribb, Ken, 1983 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Crockett, Sam L., 1985 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Crosby, Jane, 1984 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Cross, Travis, 1984-1985 (Folder 6: 14)
  - Cummings, Jim, 1983 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Curtis, Thomas, 1984-1985 (Folder 6: 16)
    Includes correspondence to Dr. Edwin J. Feulner, Jr.
  - Cutley, Clair, 1983 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Dear, J. A., 1964 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Fleming, Karl, 1968 April (Folder 6: 19)
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1965 March-April (Folder 6: 20)
  - Holderman, James, 1986, 1992, undated (Folder 6: 21)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1962 (Folder 6: 22)
  - Jarmin, Gary, 1984 (Folder 6: 23)
  - Jenkins, Jim, 1982 (Folder 6: 24)
  - L'Amour, Cathy, 1981, 1988 (Folder 6: 25)
  - Laxalt, Paul, 1987 (Folder 6: 26)
  - Long, Elaine, 2004-2005 (Folder 6: 27)
  - McKevitt, James D., 1994 (Folder 6: 28)
  - Morris, Edmund, 1989 (Folder 6: 29)
  - Orving, Marty, 1987-1988 (Folder 6: 30)
  - Patrick, Curtis, 2000 (Folder 6: 31)
  - Pinkerman, John, undated (Folder 6: 32)
  - Roberts, Oral, 1970 (Folder 6: 33)
  - Russo, Paul, 1983 (Folder 6: 34)
  - Schweiker, Richard S., 1989 (Folder 6: 35)
  - Scranton, William, 1964 (Folder 6: 36)
  - Studdert, Stephen, 1989 (Folder 6: 37)
  - Taylor, Eula, 1985 (Folder 6: 38)
  - Winchell, Walter, 1964 (Folder 6: 39)
  - Woods, Sue, 1989 June 21 (Folder 6: 40)
  - Yorty, Samuel, 1965 (Folder 6: 41)
- Richard Nixon Administration Records, Bulk, 1971-1973; 1968-1974, bulk 1971-1973 (Box 6-9)
  Includes correspondence and associated documents with Nixon and members of his staff as well as records of the Republication National Committee from 1970 to 1971. Also includes records from the California Committee for the Re-election of the President. Arranged as follows: Correspondence and Memoranda, Speech, and Subject File.
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1968-1994 (Folder 6-7)
    - Agnew, Spiro, 1971 December 27 (Folder 6: 42)
    - Armstrong, Anne, 1973 September 7 (Folder 6: 43)
    - Brummer, Clarence A., 1971 (Folder 6: 44)
    - Buchanan, Pat, 1970 (Folder 6: 45)
      Memorandum from Buchanan sent to Nofziger at Nixon's request
    - Callaway, Howard H., 1973 May 17 (Folder 6: 46)
    - Choitner, Murray, 1970 (Folder 6: 47)
    - Colson, Charles, 1970-1972 (Folder 6: 48-50)
    - Dent, Harry, 1970 January 23 (Folder 6: 51)
    - Dole, Bob, 1970 July 31 (Folder 6: 52)
    - Ford, Gerald, 1973 (Folder 6: 53)
      Includes articles about Gerald Ford
    - Frye, Alton, 1970 February-March (Folder 6: 54)
    - Haldeman, H. R. (Bob), 1969-1970 (Folder 6: 55)
    - Haldeman, H. R. (Bob), 1970-1972 (Folder 7: 1-5)
    - Harnoff, Mark and Smith, Jay, 1972 (Folder 7: 6)
    - Harwood, Dick, 1971 (Folder 7: 7)
    - Magruder, Jeb, 1971, 1973 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Nixon, Richard, 1968-1973, undated (Folder 7: 9)
    - Nixon, Richard, 1982-1989, 1994 (Folder 7: 10)
      Includes an article by Nofziger regarding Nixon following his death in 1994
    - Rumsfeld, Donald, 1972 (Folder 7: 11)
    - Simon, William E., 1975 May 21 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Stans, Maurice H., 1973 June 25 (Folder 7: 13)
    - ter Horst, Jerald F., 1974 August 15 (Folder 7: 14)
    - Timmons, William E., 1974 August 31 (Folder 7: 15)
    - Weinberger, Caspar W., 1972 December 8 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Speeches, Inaugural address, 1969 January 20 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Subject file, 1971-1973 (Folder 7-9)
    - Black vote for Nixon booklet, 1972 (Folder 7: 18)
    - California Committee for the Re-election of the President records, 1971-1973 (Folder 7-8)
      - Correspondence and related documents, 1971-1973 (Folder 7: 19-20)
      - National Hispanic Finance Committee records, 1972 (Folder 7: 21)
      - Nixon visits to California documents, 1972 (Folder 8: 1)
      - Older vote campaign documents, 1972 (Folder 8: 2-3)
      - Polls, 1972 (Folder 8: 4)
      - Region I records, 1972 (Folder 8: 5)
      - Region II records, 1972 (Folder 8: 6)
      - Region III records, 1972 (Folder 8: 7)
      - Region IV records, 1972 (Folder 8: 8)
      - Regional chairman records, 1972 (Folder 8: 9)
      - Republican National Committee records, 1972 (Folder 8: 10)
        Includes correspondence and reports specifically involving the California Committee for the Re-election of the President
      - Ripon forum records, 1972 (Folder 8: 11)
      - Voter registration materials, 1972 (Folder 8: 12)
    - Muskie, Edmund file, 1971 (Folder 8: 13)
    - Republican National Committee records, 1971-1972 (Folder 8: 14-15)
    - Republican National Committee Monday and First Monday publications, 1971-1972 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Tax bill, 1971 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Washington Education Television Station (WETA)/FM related documents, 1970-1971 (Folder 9: 3)
      Includes correspondence with Bob Dole
    - Vietnam War file, circa 1970s, 1970-1971 (Folder 9)
      - Pentagon Papers related documents, circa 1970s (Folder 9: 4)
      - Prisoner of war related documents, 1971 (Folder 9: 5)
      - Stockholm Conference, 1970 (Folder 9: 6)
    - Watergate file, 1973-1974 (Folder 9)
      - "Complete Text of the President's Watergate Transcript,", 1974 May 5 (Folder 9: 7)
        Full transcript as it was printed in the New York Times
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Folder 9: 8)
      - Magazine articles, 1973 July-August (Folder 9: 9)
      - "Nixon's Enemies" related articles and documents, 1973-1974 (Folder 9: 10)
      - Nixon resignation clippings, 1974 August (Folder 9: 11)
      - Nofziger's reflections on Watergate, circa 1974 (Folder 9: 12)
      - Nofziger's subpoena to testify before the U.S. Senate, 1973 August 8 (Folder 9: 13)
      - Clippings, circa 1974 (Folder 9: 14)
- Ronald Reagan Related Materials, 1966-2004 (Box 10-11)
  Primarily comprised of letters, memoranda, and collected printed items from Nofziger's association with Reagan. Also contains speeches and writings by Ronald Reagan from his term as governor. Arranged as follows: Correspondence, Newspaper clippings and other print media, Speeches and writings, Subject file, and Miscellany.
  - Correspondence, 1987-2000 (Folder 9)
    - Circa 1967-1976 (Folder 9: 15-16)
      Includes related documents
    - Circa 1980-1986 (Folder 9: 17)
      Includes correspondence from Nancy Reagan
    - 1991-1992, 2004, undated (Folder 9: 18)
      Includes correspondence from Nancy Reagan. Also includes a copy of Nancy Reagan's invite to Nofziger for Reagan's national funeral service and private internment in 2004, which Nofziger declined
    - Armstrong, William, 1981 (Folder 9: 19)
      Also includes correspondence to Ronald Reagan
    - Clement, Charles, 1981 (Folder 9: 20)
      Consists of correspondence from Clement to George H. W. Bush in his official capacity as Vice President regarding a U.S. citizen being held as a political prisoner in Saudi Arabia
  - Newspaper clippings and other print media, 1968-1986 (Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1968, 1976, 1979-1986 (Folder 10: 1-3)
    - Magazines featuring Ronald Reagan, 1975, 1976, 1981 (Folder 10: 4)
      Includes Newsweek, 1975 March 25; Time, 1976 August 23 and 1981 January 5
    - Nofziger's resignation as Reagan's assistant for political affairs related clippings and press releases, 1982 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Speeches and writings, 1967-1994 (Folder 10)
    Includes speeches and writings by Ronald Reagan, writings by Lyn Nofziger, and speeches and writings about Reagan by others
    - Nofziger, circa 1970s, 1980, 1981 (Folder 10)
      - Handwritten notes, circa late 1970s (Folder 10: 6)
      - 1980 presidential campaign reflections (Folder 10: 7)
      - Nofziger's notes regarding Reagan's assassination attempt, 1981 March (Folder 10: 8)
    - Ronald Reagan, 1967-1975 (Folder 10)
      - Address to the Pilgrim society, 1975 April 7 (Folder 10: 9)
      - "Excerpts of remarks by Governor Ronald Reagan,", 1969 November 17 (Folder 10: 10)
        From the Governor's Conference on California's Changing Environment
      - Radio scripts and related article drafts, circa 1975 (Folder 10: 11)
      - "Ronald Reagan speaks out on the issues,", circa 1967 (Folder 10: 12)
        This specific publication is regarding his stand on education
      - The Spirit of the Seventies, 1970, 1974 (Folder 10: 13)
        A set of pamphlets written by Reagan, each about a specific topic
      - Text of the State-of-the-State message to a Joint Session of the California State Legislature, 1970 January 6 (Folder 10: 14)
    - About Reagan by others, 1968-1994 (Folder 10-11)
      - "An Actor to Politician: The Reagan Transition" by Dave Tomshany with Gene Gregson, circa 1980s (Folder 10: 15)
        Consists of a package by the aforementioned authors outlining their book regarding Reagan, including a synopsis and chapter by chapter outline
      - "The Indifferent Figure in the Stand: A review of Ronald Reagan's collected juvenilia" by Edmund Morris, 1994 May 17 (Folder 10: 16)
        Includes a note to Nofziger from Morris
      - Letters and draft of book about Ronald Reagan based on letters written to him, circa 1970, 1975 (Folder 10: 17)